<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Updates | Bytes and Bikes]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.stevenoxley.com/blog/categories/updates/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.stevenoxley.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-11-19T21:24:29-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.stevenoxley.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steven Oxley]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm a Ham! KJ7SIL]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenoxley.com/blog/2020/11/19/im-a-ham-kj7sil/"/>
    <updated>2020-11-19T21:17:31-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenoxley.com/blog/2020/11/19/im-a-ham-kj7sil</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My ham radio license was issued this week! I have a technician class license, and my callsign is KJ7SIL.</p>

<p>Now I need to figure out how to actually make a successful transmission. I have a two-meter handheld radio that I can receive a couple of the local repeaters, but I haven&rsquo;t been able to key one of them up. Which either means that I have something misconfigured with my radio or it just doesn&rsquo;t have enough power to reach the repeaters. Hopefully my dad &ndash; who is a very experienced ham &ndash; will be able to help me figure it out when he comes to visit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[State = Busy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenoxley.com/blog/2020/08/27/state-equals-busy/"/>
    <updated>2020-08-27T23:12:58-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenoxley.com/blog/2020/08/27/state-equals-busy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been very busy, but that&rsquo;s no excuse. I&rsquo;m lowering the bar for things that deserve a blog post. This particular post will feature things I&rsquo;ve been thinking about and doing.</p>

<h2>Things that have happened</h2>

<p>My sister and her kids came to visit a couple of weeks ago. It was a fun visit! Everything was made more complicated by COVID, but it all turned out OK.</p>

<p>I crashed my mountain bike on Sunday, which was not fun. It was one of the higher speed crashes I&rsquo;ve had. My front tire washed out on a corner and I slid quite a ways, scraping up my knee (even though I was wearing knee pads) and somehow hurting my pinky, which has been the most debilitating result of the crash.</p>

<p>I received a promotion at work. I am now leading the Infrastructure squad at Seeq. This is exciting for me, since I enjoy working on cloud-based infrastructure and development tools, which is what the team is responsible for.</p>

<h2>Books I&rsquo;ve been reading</h2>

<p>I finished <em>Prey</em> by Michael Crichton. I plan to write up a book review of it soon.</p>

<p>I also finished reading <em>Being Mortal</em>, which was a superb book. I&rsquo;ll have to refer to it again the next time I&rsquo;m faced with the mortality of myself or someone I love. I should also write up a review of that book.</p>

<p>I have been working on another excellent book, which I hope to finish soon, <em>Seeking Allah, Finding Jesus</em> by Nabeel Qureshi. I&rsquo;ll post more thoughts when I&rsquo;ve finished it.</p>

<h2>Projects I&rsquo;ve been working on</h2>

<p>I have been plugging away at editing a YouTube video of a morning ride I did in Reno. It&rsquo;s been so long since I&rsquo;ve edited any video that it&rsquo;s proving a bit time consuming. I hope to have it finished and posted soon.</p>

<p>Tralina and I have also been getting more serious about cooking. Tralina purchased a Shun santoku knife, which is very nice. I will be getting a chef&rsquo;s knife soon. I have been browsing <a href="https://www.forksoverknives.com/">Forks Over Knives</a> quite excitedly, looking for recipes that look good. Today I cooked <a href="https://www.forksoverknives.com/recipes/vegan-pasta-noodles/mediterranean-vegetable-spaghetti/">Mediterranean Vegetable Spaghetti</a>, which was not very good and definitely did not meet Tralina&rsquo;s approval. I also made a <a href="https://www.forksoverknives.com/recipes/vegan-burgers-wraps/vegan-no-tuna-salad-sandwich/">&ldquo;No-Tuna&rdquo; Salad</a>, which Tralina did approve. She said that it reminded her of the tuna salad that her mom used to make before I even mentioned that it was supposed to be a tuna salad substitute. So I call that a win!</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s next</h2>

<p>It might be nice to post regular updates similar to what Sacha Chua does on <a href="https://sachachua.com/blog/">her excellent blog</a>. If I decide to do that, I&rsquo;ll probably want to come up with a consistent format.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
