<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Learning | Bytes and Bikes]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.stevenoxley.com/blog/categories/learning/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.stevenoxley.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-19T22:39:18-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.stevenoxley.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steven Oxley]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Week of Reading]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenoxley.com/blog/2014/02/19/one-week-of-reading/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-19T17:37:44-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenoxley.com/blog/2014/02/19/one-week-of-reading</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, I have been trying to read faster for about a week. My progress has been &hellip; disappointing. Granted, I have not actually &ldquo;practiced&rdquo; that much, but I have done a fair bit of regular reading, and most of the time I am conscious of trying to read faster. However, according to <a href="http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL61FFA3231514D518">the first resource I consumed</a> since embarking on this speed-reading adventure, I should spend time practicing if I really want to get fast.</p>

<p>I believe I have at least identified my main problem areas. These areas are subvocalization (&ldquo;speaking&rdquo; words in your head) and backtracking. I think subvocalization is definitely my biggest hurdle, and I&rsquo;m really not sure how I will overcome it, but I am certainly going to try. I believe the first thing I&rsquo;m going to try doing is just looking at words as fast as I can for a while, and see if that improves my speed of comprehension.</p>

<p>For reference, below is a screenshot of another test I took at <a href="http://www.freereadingtest.com/free-reading-test.html">freereadingtest.com</a>. I only got 303 wpm and 75% accuracy. Ever so slightly better than last week, but nothing remarkable. Hopefully next week is more encouraging!</p>

<p><img src="/images/freereadingtest.com.week-two.png" title="Freereadingtest.com week two" alt="Freereadingtest.com week two" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Learning to Read . . . Faster]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.stevenoxley.com/blog/2014/02/10/on-learning-to-read-faster/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T10:12:52-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.stevenoxley.com/blog/2014/02/10/on-learning-to-read-faster</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a slow reader. I have known this for a while now. I have even tried to do something about it at one point, but a recent post by my cousin made me realize just how much potential reading speed I&rsquo;m missing out on. She took the <a href="http://www.staples.com/sbd/cre/marketing/technology-research-centers/ereaders/speed-reader/">staples reading test</a> that has been going around recently and found that she reads at 748 words per minute.</p>

<p><img src="/images/staples.com.cousins-test.png" title="My cousin's staples test" alt="My cousin's reading test" /></p>

<p>By comparison, I took some tests and found that I read somewhere between 250 and 300 words per minute. And my reading comprehension is not always so good&hellip;</p>

<p><img src="/images/staples.com.my-test.png" title="My staples test" alt="My staples test" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/freereadingtest.com.first-shot.png" title="First shot at reading test" alt="My freereadingtest.com test" /></p>

<p>I took tests both at the staples website and at <a href="http://www.freereadingtest.com/free-reading-test.html">freereadingtest.com</a> (I did the Level 9 test). I want to improve my reading speed considerably. I figure that there are two ways to read more: spend more time reading and read faster. I&rsquo;ll start with reading faster, since that allows for reading more no matter the time spent reading.</p>

<p>I plan on posting weekly on my progress and what I&rsquo;ve learned and practiced. As a sneak peek for next week, here is a screenshot from a reading test I took when I was reading out loud. Tune in next week for my progress report. Hopefully I will be over 300 words per minute, but I guess we&rsquo;ll see!</p>

<p><img src="/images/freereadingtest.com.vocalizing.png" title="Vocalizing a reading test" alt="Reading out loud" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
